Guide to the William S. Johnson Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
William S. Johnson papers
1940-1992
SC0530
Johnson, William S., 1913-
60 Linear feet
Papers document his teaching and research activities and include notebooks, research reports, subject files, correspondence, grant files, reprints, and slides.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of the estate of William S. Johnson, 1997.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Johnson, professor of chemistry at Stanford University, was generally regarded as one of the major figures in 20th-century organic chemistry. He served as head of Stanford's chemistry department from 1960 to 1969, and after resigning that post, was appointed the Jackson-Wood Professor of Chemistry which he held until he became emeritus in 1978. He died in 1995.
Description of the Collection
Papers document his teaching and research activities and include notebooks, research reports, subject files, correspondence, grant files, reprints, and slides.
Access Terms
Johnson, William S.; Stanford University. Department of Chemistry. Faculty.; Chemistry, Organic.; Chemistry--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Student research report: Conrow (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Student research report: Crackett (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Student research report: Craddock (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Student research report: Crawford (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student research report: Du Bois (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Student research report: Edington (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Student research report: Hudrlik (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Student research report: Kikuchi (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Student research report: Kloek (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Student research report: Okorie (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Student research report: Ramezani (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Student research report: Silverman (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Orig. drawing for slides (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Copies of new slides (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Original slide drawings (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Not for use in Cope lecture (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Unused drawings, Cope lecture (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Copies of slides for lectures (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Slides, Trost Seminar (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Paper III Final Drawings (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - An Approach to Taxodione Involving Biomimetic Polyene Cyclization Methodology (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. Total Synthesis of dl-19-Nor-4-pregnen-20-one. Asymmetric Induction by the Initiating Center. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Formation of Vinyl Halides from Vinyl Cations Generated by Acetylenic Participation in Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Paper II (X-ray) data and suppl. material (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Paper I Final draft (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Paper IV, final draft (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - misc. papers, articles (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Figures (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Paper II, final draft and suppl., ready for duplication (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Paper III, Final draft plus suppl., ready for duplication (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Trost symposium, original drawings (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Chenera figures (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - figures, photograph negatives (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - originals, Cope lecture (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - slides (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - slides (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 2 NSF proposals (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Reprints of "Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations: A Review"; other Johnson reprints (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - John Ellwott and Ray Conrow, slide material (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Slide Material: Pfizer Vit D - Chiral Aletos talk (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Slide Material: RPI talk (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Drawings for slides (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Slide material for Cortisone talk (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Lecture at Gif: Mechanism and spironolactone synth (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Chem 133 (1975-76): "Synthesis of Steroids" (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Drawings: GM Grant Prop. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Records: Chem 223 and 225 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Slides for Cyclization Lecture (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Telefer Drawings (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Copies of Slides, 11-OH series, etc. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Control of Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations (a grant proposal for NIH) (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Student-Staff lists (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Non-Enzymic, Biogenetic-Like Cyclization of a Tetraenic Acetal to Produce the D-Homosteroid Nucleus. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Acetylenic Bond Participation in Biogenetic-Like Olefinic Cyclizations in Nitroalkane Solvents. A Facile Total Synthesis of dl-Testosterone Benzoate. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Acetylenic Bond Participation in Biogenetic-Like Olefinic Cyclizations in Nitroalkane Solvents. Synthsis of the 17-Hydroxy-5-pregnan-20-one System. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. The Synthesis and Cyclization of 2-(4-Pentenyl)-2-cyclo-hexenol. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - misc. papers (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Vinyl Fluoride Function as a Terminator of Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations Leading to Steroids. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - slides (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Reprint of article "Approaches to the Synthesis of the Insect Juvenile Hormone..."; NSF proposal (xc); part of article "Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations." (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Corticoid Synthesis via Vinylic Flouride-Terminated Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Recent Developments in Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Harrington correspondence and blueprints re: house (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Guest House and Driveway (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Improved Asymmetric Total Synthesis of Corticoids via Biomimetic Polyene Cyclization Methodology (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. Participation of the Trimethylsilylacetylenic Group and the Total synthesis of the D-Homosteroid System. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Direct Formation of the Steroid Nucleus by a Biometic Cylcization (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations: Angewandte Chemie (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclization. Trapping of the Resultant Carbocation by Internal Nucleophiles. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. Asymmetric Induction by a Chiral Center Remote from the Initiating Cationic Center. 11a-Methylprogesterone. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. Participation of the Trimethylsilylacetylenic Group as a Terminator and the Total Synthesis of a D-Homosteroid. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. Participation of the Methylacetylenic Terminator and Nitroalkanes. A Synthesis of Testosterone. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. A Review. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. Asymmetric Induction in the Cyclization of a Dienic Acetal. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Participation of the Styrene Group as a Terminator of Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. Formation of the trans-8-Methylhydrindane Ring Systems. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - New Projects. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - misc. notes and publications (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - misc. notes and publications (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - misc. notes and publications (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Goodies (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. How the Phenylacetylenic Compares with the Styryl Terminator in Influencing the Stereoselectivity of the Process. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. Synthesis of Racemic 19-Norprogesterone. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. Participation of the Phenylacetylenic Group as a Terminator and the Formation of C/D Cis Steroidal Products. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Novel Synthesis of Longifolene. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Stereospecific Total Synthesis of Racemic 11a-Hydroxyprogesterone via a Biomimetic Polyene Cyclization. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Applications of Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations to Steroid Synthesis. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cyclization of 1,3-Dimethyl-2-(trans, trans-7,11-dimethyl-3,7,11-dodecatrienyl)-2-cyclohexenol to Give the D-Homosteroid Nucleus. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Nonenzymic, Biogenetic-like Cyclization of a Trienic Acetal (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Nonenzymic Biogenetic-like Cyclizations (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Concerning the Mechanism of a Nonenzymic Biogenetic-Like Olefinic Cyclization (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Synthesis and Cyclization of 4-(trans, trans-7,12-Dimethyl-3,7,11-tridecatrienyl)-3-methyl-2-cyclohexen-1-ol and of its Allylic Isomer. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Cyclization of 4-(trans-3,7-Octadienyl)-3-methyl-2-cyclohexene-1-ol and 4-(trans, trans-7-methyl-3,7,11-dodecatrienyl)3-methyl-2-cyclohexen-1-ol. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Cyclization of 1-Methyl-6-(trans, trans-7,11-dimethyl-3,7,11-dodecatrienyl)-2-cyclohexene-1-ol. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 11a-hydroxyprogesterone (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 11a-hydroxy; Brinkmeyer, Uyaya (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 11-methyl progesterone (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 11-allyl progesterone (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Styryl Terminator--Discussion (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 11a-hydroxyprogesterone (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Styryl Terminator--Discussion (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 11a OH progesterone (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Stereoselective Indication etc. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - notes (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Total Synthesis of Spironolactone and 19-Norspironolacetone by Biomimetic Polyene Cyclization Methodology. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations. Participation of the Allysilane Group as a Terminator to Form Steroid-Like Products. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - The Propargylsilane Function as a Terminator of Biomimetic Polyene Cyclizations Leading to Steroids. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Misc. notes (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Misc. notes (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Misc. notes (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Misc. notes (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Misc. notes (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Misc. notes (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 11a-hydroxyprogesterone (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dreyfus Foundation correspondence (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - U.S.-Brazil Study group (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - General correspondence, A (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - General correspondence, B (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - General correspondence, C (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - General correspondence, D (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - General correspondence, E (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - General correspondence, F (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - General correspondence, G (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - General correspondence, H (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - General correspondence, I (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - General correspondence, J (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - General correspondence, K (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - General correspondence, L (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - General correspondence, M (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - General correspondence, N (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - General correspondence, O (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - General correspondence, P (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - General correspondence, Q-R (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - General correspondence, S (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - General correspondence, T (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - General correspondence, U-V (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - General correspondence, W (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - General correspondence, X-Y-Z (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Lectures Given, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Lectures Given, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Lectures Given, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Lectures Given, 1960, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Lectures given, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Lectures, 81-86 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Lectures Given, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Party, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Roger Adams Award (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cardiac Glycosides (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Johnson Honors Thesis (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Johnson, Problem and Paper, Benzolepidines (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Johnson reprints (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Student Research Report: Andrew, Bartlett (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Student Research Report: Brandstadter, Demnitz (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Student Research Report: Buchanan (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Student Research Report: Cheng, Conrow (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Student Research Report: Czekis, Fish, Jones (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Student Research Report: Fletcher (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Student Research Report: Plummer (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Student Research Report: Lai, Sen (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Student Research Report: Sudhakar (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Student Research Report: Pulla Reddy, Vuligonda (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Student Research Report: Moloney (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Student Research Report: Chenera (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Student Research Report: Gao, Heradan, Liu (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Student Research Report: Steele (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Student Research Report: Seetha (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Student Research Report: Marlowe, Newton (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Student Research Report: Lindell, Ramezani, Silverman, Telfer (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Student Research Report: Chan, Crackett, Craddock, Kelson (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Misc. memos, notes (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Misc. reports, grant applications (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Student Research Report: Andrews (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Student Research Report: Arnold (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Student Research Report: Atkinson (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Student Research Report: Bailey (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Student Research Report: Bannister (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Student Research Report: Banerjee (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Student Research Report: Bartmann (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Student Research Report: Bauer (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Student Research Report: Belew (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Student Research Report: Berner (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Student Research Report: Biellman (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Student Research Report: Birkeland (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Student Research Report: Birkeland (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Student Research Report: Silverman (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Student Research Report: Brinkmeyer (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Student Research Report: Brot (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Student Research Report: Brown (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Student Research Report: Bryson (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Student Research Report: Bumpus (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Student Research Report: Burckhardt (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Student Research Report: Campbell (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Student Research Report: Calzada (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Student Research Report: Cameron (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Student Research Report: Cannoy (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Student Research Report: Cannon (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Student Research Report: Chen (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Student Research Report: Cheung (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Student Research Report: Chinn (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Student Research Report: Clement (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Student Research Report: Cohen (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Student Research Report: Cole (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Student Research Report: Conrow (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Student Research Report: Cox (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Student Research Report: Craddock (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Student Research Report: Crackett (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Student Research Report: Crawford (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Student Research Report: Darb (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Student Research Report: Darling (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Student Research Report: Davis (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Student Research Report: Dehm (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Student Research Report: Della (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Student Research Report: Dewalt (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Student Research Report: Dolak (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Student Research Report: Dominguez (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Student Research Report: Doshan (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Student Research Report: DuBois (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Student Research Report: Dumas (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Student Research Report: Dunathan (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Student Research Report: Dunnigan (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Student Research Report: Dutta (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Student Research Report: Dutta (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Student Research Report: David (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Student Research Report: Eastham (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Student Research Report: Erickson (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Student Research Report: Fedoruk (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Student Research Report: Giarrusso (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Student Research Report: Dolfini (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Student Research Report: Ganem (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Student Research Report: Garst (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Student Research Report: Glenn (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Student Research Report: Gopalan (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Student Research Report: Graber (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Student Research Report: Graham (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Student Research Report: Gutsche (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Student Research Report: Hadler (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Student Research Report: Haag (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Student Research Report: Harbert (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Student Research Report: Harsey (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Student Research Report: Herrin (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Student Research Report: Highet (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Student Research Report: Hundersinn (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Student Research Report: Hirschmann (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Student Research Report: Huesmann (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Student Research Report: Huffman (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Student Research Report: Hunt (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Student Research Report: James (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Student Research Report: Jaques (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Student Research Report: Jensen (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Student Research Report: Jones (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Student Research Report: Johns (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Student Research Report: de Jongh (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Student Research Report: Kemp (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Student Research Report: Kinnel (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Student Research Report: Kloss (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Student Research Report: Kobal (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Student Research Report: Kluiber (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Student Research Report: Le Maire (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Student Research Report: Leopold (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Student Research Report: Livinghouse (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Student Research Report: Lewls (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Student Research Report: Lindell (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Student Research Report: Marshall (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Student Research Report: McCloskey (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Student Research Report: Mercury (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Student Research Report: Miller (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Student Research Report: Moyer (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Student Research Report: misc. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Student Research Report: Myers (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Student Research Report: Nabney (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Student Research Report: Nederlof (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Student Research Report: Okorie (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Student Research Report: Okuda (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Student Research Report: Pappo (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Student Research Report: Pappo (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Student Research Report: Phillips (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Student Research Report: Pike (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Student Research Report: Rapala (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Student Research Report: Rogier (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Student Research Report: Rogier (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Student Research Report: Pilar Saiz (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Student Research Report: Sausen (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Student Research Report: Schmid (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Student Research Report: Schneider (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Student Research Report: Shafer (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Student Research Report: Schmid (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Student Research Report: Soukop (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Student Research Report: Shulman (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Student Research Report: Stork (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Student Research Report: Telfer (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Student Research Report: Tews (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Student Research Report: Tsatsos (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Student Research Report: Wang (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Student Research Report: Warnhoff (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Student Research Report: Wood (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Student Research Report: Wolf (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Student Research Report: Wynberg (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Misc. reports, bulk data (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Trost, Barry awards (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Trost, Barry awards (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Health Insurance 1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Medicare (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Stanford University Clinic (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Mason Health insurance claims (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Johnson symposium 1987 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Johnson reprint Tetrahedron Prize for Creativity in Organic Chemistry: "50 Years of Research" (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Johnson Chemistry textbook (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Fish research reports, publications (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Projects I B. 2. decortexolone (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Projects I B. 3. (17),20-nolester approach (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - I B corticoids. 4. allenic substrat (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - I B corticoids. 5. 8,9-dehydro approach (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - I C 1. Lynestrenol (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - I C 2. 19-norsteroids; 7-oxo approach, pp 20-23 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - I D pp 24-30; Chenodesoxycholic acid (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Scheme 1 (paper 7) IA (1 and 2) (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Scheme 2 (paper 231) I A (3) (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Scheme 3 (Fagundo and Ravelo) I C (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Scheme 4 (paper 229) I B (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Scheme 5 (paper 224 and Thompson et al.) I D (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Scheme 6 I F (Wang) (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Scheme 7 a, b and c II (Chen) (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Scheme 8 I G (James, Chen, Livinghouse) (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Scheme 9a (p. 13) V pro-c-7 cycl.; Scheme 9a (p. 14) VI de Spirono lecture (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Scheme 10 VII (paper 15) Zeslin et al.; See scheme 8, ged prof. (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Scheme 11 abcd IX (vinyl halides), paper 8 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Scheme 12 X (paper 16) (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Scheme 13 III (Elliott, Hanson) (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Scheme 14 (paper 18), Homoallylic alcs (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Scheme 15 (paper 19) (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Scheme 16 (paper 20) (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Crotylsilane Problem (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Benalized method (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - G. M. Amino acids (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - A-Methylene butyrolactone (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Acetols of Ketones (erythovolide A) (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Ionophore Antibiotics; Ireland synthesis (methallyl silane) (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - I F Basic Stgudies, pp. 54-62 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Project I A. 1. Lanosteroid. 2. C-17 side chain. (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Project I B. Synthesis of corticoids. 1. "Ideal" terminator. (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence and paper draft (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Prep of Chiral diols (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - reprints (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Gao, Yun Final Report "Acyclical Stereoselection" (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - misc. correspondence, reports (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Research proposal (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - HRMS spectra related to B-Amyrin paper (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Pieter Nederlof (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Research proposal evaluation, reprints. (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - II B Synthesis via Acetols. 1. Pyrathroids. 2. Potato stress met. (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous Methods for acyclic and cyclic stereoselections (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Acetols with hetero atoms other than 0 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - II A Chiral Acetal Variants. 72-78 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Chiral Auxiliaries other than acetals (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Dialkyl Ketene Acetals (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - I. E. Vit. D3 metabolites pp. 31-53 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Gloria Li. MS #2. (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Cope Award (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Vit. D3 metabolites (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Acetal aldol (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - reprints (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Old seminar schedules (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Newspaper article, reprints, review articles. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Notes (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Reprints. NSF Progress Report. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Reprints and Preprints: Zeelen, Stetherlance. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Chiral Acetal Problems (Box 11, Folder 5)